我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
那你为了保护我还会再做多少可怕的事呢
How many more terrible things are you gonna do to protect me?
这才是我要做的  这才是重要的
That's my job. That's all that matters.
我要独自到外面闯一闯
It's my turn to go out on my own.
请不要来找我
Don't come looking for me.
一切似乎都在告诉我
Everything seems to be telling me
我和巴里注定要在一起
that Barry and I are meant to be together.
谁来救救我
Somebody please help!
现在只有一个人能救你
There's only one person who can help you now.
用你的速度交换沃利
闪电侠
The Flash.
巴里  我知道你不能把你的速度给那怪物
Barry, I know you can't give up your speed to that monster.
决定权在我
That's not your decision.
交出他来  速度给你
Hand him over and it's yours.
他慢下来了  他又要变成普通人了
He's slowing down. He's becoming human again.
我知道你心里是在乎过我的
I know some piece of you did care for me.
求求你放了他
Please let him go.
凯特琳
Caitlin!
中城里普通的一天
It's a regular day in Central City.
没什么不一样
Nothing out of the ordinary.
人们醒来
People wake up.
起床
Roll out of bed.
穿上衣服准备出门
Suit up for the day.
尽快赶去工作
Get to work as fast as they can.
上班路上买一杯咖啡
Make sure they get a caffeine fix along the way
才能保证他们能撑过等待他们的
so they can make it through the mountain of work
成堆的工作
that awaits them.
没错  只是普通的一天
Yup, it's just a regular day.
而我也只是个普通人
And I'm just a regular guy.
我真希望我们不用留着杰伊的头盔
I really wish we didn't have to keep Jay's helmet around.
我狠这玩意
I hate this thing.
真想把它砸烂
Just want to put a dent in it.
西斯科  你用震波看到凯特琳了吗
Cisco, did you see Caitlin in your vibe?
极速把她关到他的巢穴里了
Zoom's got her in his lair.
她很害怕  但是她没事
She's scared, but she's okay.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
好吧  我们需要救她出来
All right, we need to get her back.
我知道
I know.
但是没了你的速度
But without your speed,
我们没办法穿过
there's no way any of us can get through that breach
西斯科在医院找到的缺口
that Cisco found at the hospital.
我觉得现在我们无能为力了
I just don't think there's anything we can do right now.
他说的对
He's right.
这都要感谢你了  小艾
And it's thanks to you, Al.
够了  我们谁都不好过
Enough. We're all suffering here.
没错  没错  警探
That's right. That's right, Detective.
我们都不好过  我们失去了斯诺
We're all suffering. We've lost Snow,
你丢了你的速度  而现在
you've lost your speed, and now...
现在极速可以随时穿过缺口
now Zoom can come through that breach anytime he wants.
而这  艾伦
And that, Allen...
是你的错
that's on you.
我们都有错  好吗
Hey, that's on all of us, okay?
我们一起做的决定
We made these decisions as a team.
我们没有
No we didn't.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
在极速再次抓走杰西之前
I'm gonna go find Jesse
我得找到她
before Zoom does...again.
等等  你找到她了吗  怎么做的
Wait, you found her? How?
信号死区  远程...
Cellular dead zones, remote--
我地球上的人发出的频率和
people from my Earth vibrate at a different frequency
你们地球上的不同
than people from your Earth.
他们会在所到之处留下信号死区
They leave cellular dead zones wherever they go.
所以我在你身边才老是没信号吗
That's why I'm always dropping calls around you?
好吧  等等  那有什么用
Okay, so--so wait, how did that help?
我追踪到杰西来这里之后制造的死区
I track the dead zones created by Jesse since she got here
然后我顺着信号
and I follow the trail.
很简单
It's easy.
怎么  你觉得你需要那把枪
What, so you think you're gonna need that gun
才能劝服她和你一起离开吗
to convince her to leave with you?
你今天问题可真多啊  韦斯特
You're full of questions today, aren't you, West?
这枪不是为我女儿准备的
The gun is not for my daughter.
不只是她从别的地球而来
She's not the only person from a different Earth,
还藏在这个地球上
hiding out on this one
如果我碰到了别的人  我就需要这个了
If I run into them, I'm gonna need this.
好吧  但你也需要帮忙
Okay, but you're also gonna need some help.
真的吗
Really?
你认识谁有那速度可以帮我的吗  拉蒙
You know anyone with the speed to help me, Ramon?
太好了  我去我的工作室了
Great. I'll be in my workshop.
别听威尔斯的  巴里
Don't listen to Wells, Barry.
这不都是你的错
This ain't all on you.
是  我知道
Yeah, I know.
你需要搭车回警局吗
You need a ride back to the station?
不用了
No, I'm good.
其实我想待在这
I'm gonna stick around, actually.
今早我就完成了所有的案子
Finished all my cases this morning.
速度真快
Damn, that was fast.
用词不当
That was a poor choice of words.
你知道自己可以慢慢恢复到
You do know it's okay to ease back into
过去的行事方式的  对吗
the way you used to do things, right?
这是我打击犯罪的唯一方式
Well, this is the only way I can fight crime.
如果我不是闪电侠  我也只能这样了
If I'm not The Flash, that's what I got to do.
你要吃点东西
You need to eat.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
如果你想和我说话  先把面具脱掉
If you want to speak to me, then take off that mask.
这样感觉好点了吗
Does this make you feel better?
你无论做什么都不可能让我好受
Nothing you could ever do would make me feel better.
你不需要害怕
You don't need to be afraid.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
我太在意你  所以不会做出那种事
I care too much about you to do that.
你在意的只有自己...
You only care about yourself...
亨特
Hunter.
睁大眼睛看好了  儿子
You're gonna want to see this, son.
不
No!
我知道你觉得我是个魔鬼
I know you think that I'm a monster.
我知道为什么
I understand why.
但那会改变的
But that'll change.
-拜托  凯特... -不要这么叫我
- Please, Cait-- - Do not call me that.
你为什么把我关在这里
Why are you keeping me here?
你已经痊愈了
You're cured.
你根本不需要我了
You don't need me for anything.
你在这里是因为我爱你
You're here because I love you.
或许需要一段时间  但是终有一天
It may take a while, but someday,
你会重新对我产生同样的感觉
you'll start feeling that way about me again, too.
别拘束
Make yourself at home.
你在这里要呆上一段时间了
You're gonna be here a while.
好吗
Okay?
我不明白
I-I don't understand.
你好  我的二重身
Well, hello, doppelganger of mine.
真是出人意料啊
What do you know?
深肤色的我也挺不错
I can still pull off brunette.
中城警局
老爸
Dad.
儿子  真是个惊喜
Oh, hey, son. What a surprise.
怎么了
What's up?
我想问你点事
I wanted to ask you about something.
其实是某个人
Someone, actually.
闪电侠
The Flash.
他怎么了
What about him?
爱瑞丝受伤时  他出现在我街道赛车的地方
Well, he showed up at my street race when Iris got hurt.
人形鲨鱼攻击我们家时他也出现了
Then, when that man-shark thing attacked our house.
极速把我掳走时  他说
And when Zoom took me, he said,
"闪电侠认识的人在乎我"
"Someone The Flash knew cared about me"
傻瓜都能看出来那人是你
Yeah, it doesn't take a genius to figure out that that's you.
你想让我告诉你闪电侠是谁吗
You want me to tell you who he is?
我不能
I can't do that.
不  我知道
No, I know. I know.
其实我是希望你能替我安排一场会面
I was actually hoping that you could set up a meeting for me.
会面  你和他吗
A meeting? Between you and him?
这我也不知道能不能做到  沃利
I don't know if I can do that either, Wally.
为什么不行呢
Well, why not?
乔
Joe?
辛格要见你
Singh wants to see you.
好吧...
Okay. Um...
听着  或许某一天可以  但现在不行
Look, maybe one day, but, I mean, not now.
我要去工作了
I got to get to work.
回家见
See you at home?
好
All right.
激光标签俱乐部在2D室
The laser tag club's in 2D.
什么  不
The--? Oh, no.
我找杰西
I'm looking for Jesse.
请进
Come on in.
多谢
Thanks.
杰西
Jesse!
你好像是第一个来找她的人
You're, like, the first person who's ever come to visit her.
-什么  -你怎么找到我的
- What? Oh. - How'd you find me?
杰西...
Jess...
这里手机都没有信号
Uh, cellular dead zone.
我告诉过你  无论你去哪我都会找到你
I told you, I'd find you wherever you went.
慢着  所以你是离家出走的吗
Wait, so you're a runaway?
你是她爸吗
So you're her dad?
很好  我需要找一个新室友的话告诉我
Great, let me know if I need to find a new roommate.
听着
Listen.
我们得离开这里
We need to go.
为什么呢
So, what?
你觉得我和你在一起会更安全吗
You think I'll be safer with you?
没错
Yes.
我还是不离开了
Yeah, I think I'm gonna pass.
杰西
Jesse.
我们得离开这里
We need to leave.
不行  好吗
No, okay?
我不会再和你去任何地方了
No, I'm not going anywhere with you ever again.
你...
You are...
你处于危险中
you are in danger.
你懂吗  你处于极度危险中
Do you understand? You are in grave danger.
我知道
I know!
我是因为你才身陷危险的
I'm in danger because of you.
-因为我  -是啊
- Because of me? - Yeah!
发生的一切都是你的错
Okay, everything that's happened, it's your fault.
极速追杀我们  那些超能力者
Zoom hunting us, the metas...
我搬来这里
moving here.
我受够了
I'm done with it.
你希望我开始新的生活
Okay, you wanted me to start a new life,
而我正在努力去做
and that is exactly what I'm trying to do.
-不  杰西  杰西  -你杀了人
- No, Jess-- Jess-- - You killed a man!
我无法原谅你
I can't just forgive you for that.
也许我害怕极速  但是
And I may be afraid of Zoom, but...
但是我也一样害怕你
but I am just as afraid of you.
求你  你走吧
Please, just-- just go.
切勿跨越警戒线
一份新报告显示本月的轻微犯罪
And a new report shows that petty crimes have risen
稍有上升  引发了人们对闪电侠的关注
slightly this month, sparking concerns that The Flash--
别看了
Don't watch that.
西斯科  大家迟早都会发现
Cisco, everybody's gonna realize sooner or later
我失去了速度
that I don't have my speed.
越晚发现越好
The later the better.
我们最不希望城市里的每一个罪犯
The last thing we need is every criminal in the city
认为自己不必受到惩罚  对吗
thinking they're untouchable, right?
什么声音
What is that?
例证
Case in point.
什么
What?
是什么
What is that?
是哈里
It's Harry.
哈里怎么了
What about Harry?
实验室卡车的摄像头录下了一起车祸
The camera in the lab van recorded an accident.
这是我的事故协助软件
See, this is my version of crash assist.
就像俄罗斯行车记录仪  但是
It's like those Russian dash cams, but, you know,
没有武装直升机
without attack helicopters
收音机里也没播着雷人的流行乐
and bad pop music on the radio.
这看起来一点也不像是车祸
That does not look like an accident.
先是凯特琳被抓走  然后轮到威尔斯
First Caitlin's taken, now Wells.
事故协助
已激活
他是在这被抓走的
This is where he got taken,
但是那一带没有任何交通摄像头
but there aren't any traffic cams in that area.
我要去那看看有什么发现
I'm gonna head out there, see what I can find.
我会分析这段录像
I'll analyze this footage and see
看看能否查出他的身份
if we can figure out who this is.
好
All right.
等等  货车最后停在什么地方
Wait, what was the last place the van stopped?
沃德曼和海岸处
Woodmen and Shore for about 15 minutes
距离返回中城的路有十五分钟路程
before heading back to Central City.
-为什么  -杰西肯定就在那里
- Why? - That's where Jesse must be.
如果她爸爸出事  她应该知道
She should know if something's happened to her dad.
爱瑞丝
Iris, hey.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help with something.
你是  冰霜杀手
You're... Killer Frost.
你就是凯特琳·斯诺
And you're Caitlin Snow.
你的小朋友西斯科不停地说起你
Your little friend, Cisco, wouldn't shut up about you.
把你说得像个圣人似的
Made you out to be some kind of a saint.
告诉我  为何隐藏自己的好身材
So tell me, why hide the girls?
你又不是没看过我们的身材
I mean, you've seen our body, right?
如果我能让我的超能力穿越这面碳炔墙
If I could get my powers to work through this carbyne wall,
我要做的第一件事就是让他闭嘴
the first thing I would do is shut him up!
他是谁
Who is he?
不知道  也不在乎
Don't know, don't care.
如果他被关在这里  极速肯定对他有所企图
But if he's here, Zoom must need something from him.
那极速对你有什么企图
So what does Zoom need you for?
这个问题问得好  凯特琳
That is an excellent question, Caity.
我也一直在问自己同样的问题
You know, I've been asking myself the same thing.
但是现在不重要了
But doesn't matter now.
我是不会在这待太久的
I'm not gonna stick around much longer.
等等  你不是说在这间牢房里
Wait, I thought you said your powers don't work
你的能力没用吗
inside this cell?
是没用  你说得对
They don't. You're right.
所以你要帮我逃离这里
So you're gonna help me get out of here.
我为什么要帮你
Why would I help you?
亲爱的  就凭你一人之力
Listen, honey, there's no way you are
你是下不了那个悬崖的
making it down that cliff all by yourself.
我们不如做个交易吧
So let's make a deal.
你帮我离开这间牢房
You get me out of this box,
我就帮助你回家
and I'll help you get home.
也许我还会免费指点你一些穿衣技巧
Might even throw in some wardrobe tips for free.
你意下如何  凯特琳
So what do you say, Caitlin?
同意吗
Do we have a deal?
我不明白
I don't understand.
周围什么也没有
There's nothing around here.
货车是怎么撞上的
What did the van hit?
不知道
I don't know.
足够强大的事物施以相同的力量
Something strong enough to exert an equal amount of force
撞击了货车
back on the van.
肯定有人来过这里
Someone was definitely here, though.
你觉得可能是超能力者吗
You think maybe a meta-human?
是的
Yeah.
如果是追杀威尔斯的超能力者
And if it's a meta that's after Wells--
那他们可能是地球二的人
Then they could be from Earth-2.
有可能
Probably.
我们得去找杰西
We got to get Jesse.
要快点找到威尔斯
Find Wells. Fast.
哈里森·威尔斯博士
Dr. Harrison Wells.
我是  你是什么人
Yup. And who are you?
我叫格里芬·格雷
Name's Griffin Grey.
格里芬·格雷
Griffin Grey?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
不  但你该认识的
Nope. But you should.
我是你的错误之一
I'm one of your mistakes.
你种下的这个恶果要来报复你了
One of your sins coming home to roost.
好吧  你以为我
All right, you think I...
我来自
I'm from...
我不是  我不是你想的那个人
I'm not--I'm not who you think I am.
你是谁我可清楚得很
I know exactly who you are.
你得补救你的粒子加速器对我的伤害
And you're gonna fix what your particle accelerator did to me.
粒子加速器把你怎么了
What did the accelerator do to you?
就这样
That.
好吧  真厉害
Well, that's impressive.
考虑所有因素
And all things considered,
我不明白为什么获得那样的力量
I don't know that having that kind of strength is the worst thing
对你会是最糟糕的事
you could have been given.
对  我起初也是这么想的
Yeah, that's what I thought at first.
而且这有趣极了
And it was a lot of fun.
直到我发现它对我还有别的影响
Till I learned it did something else to me, too.
这是我
That's me.
去年的样子
Last year.
你在
You're...
你在衰老
you're ageing.
如果这么继续下去  我几个月内就会死
If this keeps happening, I'll be dead in a few months.
你多大了  格里芬
How old are you, Griffin?
我十八岁
I'm 18.
听我说
Look.
我很抱歉这事发生在你身上
I'm sorry this is happening to you.
但我没有办法补救它
But there's nothing I can do to fix it.
好吧  那真是糟透了
Well, that sucks.
因为如果你找不到办法帮我  威尔斯博士
'Cause if you can't figure out a way to help me, Dr. Wells...
那你也将命不久矣了
You're gonna die soon, too.
我就不该离开的
I never should have left.
不  这不是你的错
No, this isn't your fault.
知道是谁带走他的吗
Do we know what took him?
这就是有意思的地方
That's where things get interesting.
你们带回来的指纹
That fingerprint that you guys brought in,
-就是货车上的那个  -对  怎么了
- the one from the van, I mean. - Yeah, yeah.
是属于这个人的
Belongs to this guy.
格里芬·格雷
Griffin Grey.
中城高中的一个高三学生
A senior at Central City High School?
不  等下  我之前看过这孩子的照片
No, wait, I've seen this kid's picture before.
他失踪了  大约六个月前
He went missing, like, six months ago.
没错
That's right.
这说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
绑架威尔斯的可不是个十八岁的孩子
An 18-year-old didn't kidnap Wells.
我本来也是这么想的
That's what I thought at first,
但你好好看看这个
but feast your eyes on this.
格里芬·格雷
匹配
这是同一个人
It's the same guy.
是的  血样也证实了
Yeah, the blood sample confirms it.
这怎么可能呢
How is that even possible?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
凯特琳不在  我没法从分子水平
Without Caitlin here, I can't really analyze the cells
分析这些细胞  来了解这是什么情况
on a molecular level to see what we're dealing with here.
我或许能帮上忙
You know, I might actually be able to help.
怎么帮
How?
生物化学是我的大学专业之一
Bio-chem was one of my majors in college.
你的专业之一
One of your majors?
你有几个专业
How many did you have?
五个
Five.
怎么  在这里不常见吗
What, is that not common here?
姐们  不  这事在哪儿都不常见
Girl, no, that is not common anywhere.
好吧  我们搜索那个格雷
All right, let's search for that Grey,
看看能找出点什么
see what we come up with.
我试试面部识别能不能找到他
I'll see if facial recognition brings him up
我也让乔查下中城警局的数据库
and I'll have Joe check CCPD's database.
好的
Cool.
看看你能做点什么
See what you can do.
时间不多了
Tick tock, tick tock.
我已经尽可能快了
I'm going as fast as I can.
那你最好再快一点
Well, you better go faster.
极速随时都有可能回来
Zoom will be back any minute.
我可以就把你丢在这儿  你知道吗
I could just leave you in there, you know.
但你实在太想回家了
But you want to go home so badly.
你是怎么变成这样的
So how did this happen to you?
某天醒来  浑身发冷  脸色苍白
Woke up one day, cold, pale.
我以为自己生病了
Thought I was sick.
结果发现完全是另一回事
Turns out it was something else entirely.
你在粒子加速器爆炸时
You got hit by the dark matter from
被暗物质击中了吗
the particle accelerator explosion?
是的
Yes.
就在我被医学院勒令退学之后
Right after I flunked out of med school.
我得搬回去和我母亲住
Had to move back in with my mother.
那肯定很不好受
That couldn't have been fun.
我是说  如果她像我母亲一样
If she's anything like mine, I mean.
为什么
Why?
你母亲也是个冷漠的自恋狂吗
Is yours a frigid narcissist, too?
冷血极了
Cold as ice.
是啊
Yeah.
我妈妈自从查理死后就那样了
Mom was like that ever since Charlie died.
查理是谁
Who's Charlie?
我的弟弟
My brother.
-我从来没有兄弟  -是吗
- I never had a brother. - No?
那为何妈妈在你的地球上那么讨厌
Then why was mom such a bitch on your Earth?
其实我也不知道
Honestly, I couldn't say.
那...
So...
这个怎么帮我逃出这里
how is this going to get me out of here?
电缆里的电流应该能加热碳炔
The electrical current in the cable should heat up the carbyne,
然后能反过来加速电子
which in turn should speed up the electrons
电子运动得越快
and the faster they go--
碳炔的分子结构就越脆弱
The weaker its molecular structure becomes.
没错
Exactly.
我有时也会学习
I studied every once in a while.
等热度够了
Well, when it gets hot enough,
碳炔就会像玻璃一样易碎
it should make the carbyne as fragile as glass.
那咱俩就可以逃出去了
And then we can both get out of here.
-沃利  -你好  乔
- Wally. - Hey, Joe.
怎么了
What's up?
你看着像有心事
You look like you got something on your mind.
对
Yeah, I do.
别告诉我  你大老远开车过来
Please don't tell me you drove all the way over here
又是为了闪电侠的事
to ask about The Flash again.
这...
It's...
这不可能的  沃利
it's not happening, Wally.
可...就这一次  我就这个要求
But...it's just one time. That's all I'm asking.
不可能
It's impossible.
他救了我的命  乔
He saved my life, Joe.
我得感谢他
I owe him a thank you.
听着
Look.
我这辈子一直都鲁莽大意
I've been reckless my whole life.
玩赛车  挑战极限
Racing cars, pushing limits.
做什么都开足马力  什么都不考虑
I did everything at full speed without a care in the world.
可直到极速抓了我
But it wasn't until Zoom took me that...
我才真的担心小命不保
that I really thought I was gonna die.
要不是闪电侠出手相救
And I was going to die,
我就真的会死掉
if The Flash didn't do what he did.
他为了救我放弃了自己的超能力
He gave up his powers to save me.
他甚至都不认识我
A guy he didn't even know.
之前从来没人为我那么做过
No one's ever done anything like that for me before.
我得告诉他  那对我意义重大
I need to tell him how much that means to me.
那好吧
Well, all right.
给我点时间
Just give me a little while.
我看看有什么办法
I'll see what I can do.
我得走了
I got to go.
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
多谢
Thanks.
这里
In here.
我收到你的短信了  怎么了
I got your text. What's up?
好  人脸识别刚检测到
All right, facial recognition
格雷闯进了纽伯里大道上的
just picked up Grey breaking into Ace Chemical
埃斯化学公司
down on Newbury Road.
-我爸爸和他一起吗  -还不知道
- Is my dad with him? - I don't know yet.
-咱们得去一趟  -你确定吗
- But we have to go. - Uh, you sure about that?
我确定  我们不能在这干坐着
Yeah, I'm sure. Look--we can't just sit here.
不管我的速度在不在
Regardless of whether I have my speed or not,
我都得想办法帮忙  这点永远不会变
I have to try to help. That's never gonna change.
好
Okay.
我跟你去  但咱们需要后援
I'm with you, but we're gonna need some backup.
-乔在路上了  -我也去
- Joe's on his way. - I'm coming with.
别  你就待在这里
No, look, please just stay here.
我们还不知道要对付的是什么
We don't know what we're dealing with yet.
你把血样测试做完就好
Just finish running the test on the blood sample.
抱歉  多谢了  杰西
I'm sorry. Thank you, Jesse.
格里芬·格雷  中城警局
Griffin Grey, CCPD!
待那里别动
Stay right there.
你绑架了哈里森·威尔斯
The man that you kidnapped, Harrison Wells,
你得把他放了
you need to let him go.
不行  现在还不行
I can't do that. Not yet.
那我们只能来硬的了
Then we'll have to do this the hard way.
我想也是
I guess so.
好吧  "超人希曼"力气不小
Okay, He-Man's got some power.
瞄得还挺准
And accuracy.
好  分散他的注意  好吗
All right, keep him distracted, okay?
什么  巴里  巴里
What? Barry! Barry!
我能这么扔一个晚上
I can do this all night.
我们只想要威尔斯  放了他
We just want Wells. Just let him go.
账没算完不能放他走
Not until I'm done with him!
太慢了
Too slow.
巴里
Barry!
我想我需要医疗护理
Oh, I think I need some medical attention.
他的基因其实已经突变了
So his genes have actually mutated.
我用巴里找到的血样做了DNA检测
I ran the DNA from the blood sample Barry found,
他细胞里的功能性肌肉抑制素基本没有了
and the functional myostatin in his cells is essentially gone.
那是他超能力的来源
I mean, giving him super-strength.
各位  还有一件事
Guys, there's something else.
我亲眼看见他衰老了
Um, I saw him age.
就在我面前
Right in front of me.
他正遭受氧化应激
He's suffering from oxidated stress.
也就是说他体内DNA里的蛋白质
It means the protein in the DNA in his body
正被氧化剂侵蚀
are being ravaged by oxidants.
所以他得多吃点蓝莓吗
So, what, he needs to up his blueberry intake?
不  这意味着他越是运用超能力
No, it means, uh, the more he exerts himself,
就衰老得越快
the faster he ages.
如果我们让他过度消耗能量
So if we can get him to exert too much energy--
他就会变得年老体弱
Then he'll become old and weak.
那我们该怎么做
And how do you think we're gonna do that?
我可不能让他把你当人肉吊袋狂揍
I can't watch you be a human punching bag
直到他变成辛普森爷爷
until he turns into Grandpa Simpson.
我想这个我们能解决
I think we can fix that.
杰西  我需要你的快速思维能力
Jesse, I'm gonna need some of that quick thinking of yours.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
我得先回局里去了
I got to get back to the station.
你还好吗
You okay?
不  不太好
No, not really.
你知道吗  我获得超能力后
You know, you were the first person I saved
你是我救的第一个人
after I got my powers?
我们当时在外面散步
We were out on a walk
谈论着艾迪
and we were talking about Eddie
以及你们怎么走到一起
and how you were with him,
我当时就想
and I was thinking to myself
我昏迷时错过了多少事情
how I missed a lot while I was in that coma.
突然间  那些车就朝我们冲过来了
And then all of a sudden, those cars came at us.
然后世界好像就静止了
And it was like the world froze.
就像  世上只有我们两个人
Like... you and I were the only two people in the world.
我当时还不知道我有那种力量
I didn't even know what I could do yet,
但我很肯定我能救你
but I knew that I could save you.
我也做到了
And I did.
而现在  我不知道  我不
And now, I don't know. I don't...
我连自己是谁都不知道了
I just don't even know who I am anymore
或者我应该是谁
or who I'm supposed to be.
巴里  你应该是你一直都是的那个人
Barry, you're supposed to be the same guy that you've always been.
不管是不是穿着战衣
Suit or no suit...
那个人都是个英雄
that guy is a hero.
你要的东西都在这了
That's everything you asked for.
你晚上怎么睡得着
How do you sleep at night?
想到自己毁了那么多人的生活
Knowing you've destroyed so many people's lives?
我睡不着
I don't.
你生命中有什么人是你关心的吗
Do you have anyone in your life that you care about?
我有个女儿
I have a daughter.
我生命中曾有个我关心的人
I used to have someone in my life that I cared about.
我的女朋友  珍妮
My girlfriend, Jenny.
我们本会结婚  将来还会有孩子
We were gonna get married, have kids someday.
但当我被粒子加速器的冲击波击中之后
But after I got hit by that wave from the particle accelerator,
我所有的梦想都终结了
all my dreams ended.
你知道吗  我有时会看到她在街上走
You know, I see her sometimes, walking down the street.
她甚至认不出我来
She doesn't even recognize me.
她又怎么可能认得呢
But why would she?
我看上去和她爸爸一样老
I look as old as her dad.
你把她从我身边夺走了
You robbed me of her.
格里芬  别说了
Griffin. Stop talking.
不然我没法集中注意力
So I can concentrate.
醒醒吧  哥们
Wake up, man.
这座城市因为你而变得一团糟
This city is screwed up because of you.
它原本那么平静和正常
It was quiet and normal.
直到你趾高气昂地到来
Until you rode in on your high horse,
谈论着科学和改变未来
talking about science and changing the future.
你没有停下来想过
You didn't stop to think
你的粒子加速器会给他人带来怎样的影响
about what your particle accelerator could do to others.
你只想过它会为你带来什么
You only thought about what it could do for you.
够了
Enough!
Enough.
我希望你做的这一切是值得的
I hope it was worth it.
博士
Doc.
离墙远点
Stay away from the wall.
我们试试吧
Let's give it a whirl.
看来你内心还是有点狂野的
Looks like you have a little badass in you, after all.
这个人怎么办
What are we gonna do about this guy?
凯特琳
Oh, Caity.
我觉得他是回不了家了
I don't think he's ever going home.
你也是
And neither are you.
你在做什么  我们说好的
What are you doing? I thought we had a deal.
你们那个地球上的人都这么好骗吗
Ugh, is everyone on your Earth this gullible?
高跟鞋可不是冰上的最好选择  是不是
Heels aren't the best on ice, are they?
你知道吗  我一见到你
You know, once I saw you,
就明白为什么极速不杀我了
I realized why Zoom didn't kill me.
因为我跟你长得一模一样
Because I look just like you.
而现在他不需要我了
Now he won't need me anymore.
是的  我不需要了
No. I don't.
你要是帮他
Try that with him...
他也会死
he dies, too.
面部识别系统找不到线索
Not picking up anything from facial recognition.
我能找到的唯一信号死区就在这里
The only cellular dead zone I can find is the one in here.
无意冒犯
No offense.
等一下  他去找我的时候
No, wait a second, was he wearing his watch
有戴他那块手表吗
when he left to get me?
已经试过了  GPS不起作用
Already tried that. GPS isn't working.
对  但是对超能力者的活动会有反应
Okay, no, but the meta-human activity would be.
我的意思是  那块手表是用来
I mean, the watch is designed
追踪超能力者的  对不对
to track metas, right?
而既然格里芬就是超能力者
And since Griffin Grey is one,
手表会不停地发送信息到服务器
it'll keep sending a message to a server
直到被接收
till it goes through.
但因为我们在另一个地球
But since we're on a different Earth,
信息永远不会被接收
it'll never go through.
所以它会不停地发送同样的信号
So it just keeps sending the same signal.
设备位置
找到他了  中城游乐场
There he is, Central City Amusement Park.
是的  这次我要一起去
Yeah, and I'm coming with this time.
很好  我们找到哈利了
Okay, great, we've found Harry,
但要怎么阻止格雷
but how are we gonna stop Grey?
很好  你提到了这一点
I'm so glad that you asked.
我和杰西改良了战衣的内衬
Jesse and I upgraded the internal lining of the suit.
费利西蒂还给战衣镀上了矮星合金
Felicity hooked us up with some dwarfstar alloy.
等等  矮星合金
Wait, dwarfstar alloy?
这化合物也用来
It's the same compound
保护雷的原子侠战衣
that's used to protect Ray's A.T.O.M. suit.
没错
That's right.
超级坚韧  超级轻便
Super strong, super lightweight.
唯一的问题是  我们有的不多
Only thing is, we couldn't get much of it.
什么意思
All right, what does that mean?
我们手头的只够保护战衣的胸脯部分
We could only cover the chest portion of the suit.
是啊  抱歉
Yeah, sorry.
还有一点
Uh, here's the other thing,
可能不太重要  我推测
probably not a big deal-- um, I'm guessing
战衣只禁得住格雷的一击
the suit will only absorb one of Grey's punches.
再多打一下
Anything more than that,
你就会像个陶罐
you'll be like a pi?ata.
不过掉出来的不是糖果  而是...
Only it won't be candy coming out, it'll be--
-我的身体  -你...没错
- Me. - You're--yeah, you.
那好吧
All right.
希望轻松一拳就能搞定
Hopefully, one gimme punch is all I'll need.
好了
All right, then.
完成了
Finished.
这玩意能把我治好吗
This is gonna cure me?
科学点讲就是谨慎乐观
As we say in science, I'm cautiously optimistic.
在过去的两年中
You know, I learned a lot about chemistry
我学到了不少化学知识
in the past two years.
是吗
Is that right?
并且我知道在过去的半小时里
And I know all you've been doing is diluting that compound
你一直在稀释那化合物
for the past half hour.
你并不知道如何才能帮助我  对吗
You don't know how to help me, do you?
什么都帮不了你
There is no helping you.
我说了要是治不好我  你就得死
I told you you were gonna fix me or you were dead!
为什么坏人总是藏在
Why is it that bad guys always insist
让人最令人毛骨悚然的地方
on having the creepiest hideouts?
因为他们不正常
'Cause they crazy.
没错
Right.
巴里
Hey, Barry.
格雷朝你们那来了
Grey's headed your way.
快走  快走
Come on. Hey, come on.
准备好了吗
You ready?
爱瑞丝
Okay, Iris.
听我命令
On my mark.
三...
Three...
二...
two...
一
one.
点亮
Now!
你就这点能耐吗  闪电侠
That all you got, Flash?
交出威尔斯博士
I just want Dr. Wells.
我要让他治好我
And I wanted him to fix me.
但他没这个能耐
But he can't.
我搞定你以后  再去处理他
So once I finish you, I'm gonna finish him.
不许动
Freeze!
冲我来啊
Come on!
好了
Okay?
他再打一拳  我们就能活捉他
I think one more punch, and we get this guy a walker.
发现他了
Hey, guys, we got him.
他在摩天轮附近
He's over by the Ferris Wheel.
听着
Look.
我们能帮助你
We can help you.
太晚了
It's too late for that.
不是所有人都有你的超能力  闪电侠
Not everyone got the powers you did, Flash.
我们没你那么幸运
Some of us weren't so lucky.
那拳倒挺轻松
That was the gimme.
格里芬
Griffin.
快住手
Please stop.
别看我越来越衰老
I might be getting older,
我的力量却强大超前
but I'm stronger than ever.
巴里
Barry!
没事吧
You okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm good.
就不能多用点矮星合金吗
Could've used more of that dwarfstar alloy.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too.
回家真好
Home sweet home.
是啊...
Yeah, well...
说实话  这里有段时间没家的感觉了
to be honest, it hasn't felt much like a home in a while.
倒也不是因为你离开了
At least, certainly not since you left.
好吧
Yeah.
对不起  爸爸  我不该一走了之
Look, I'm sorry, Dad, for just leaving like that.
可是...
But...
你要明白
I mean, you have to understand,
你为了我才杀掉那个人
I'm the reason you killed that man.
这是多么沉重的负担
And that's a really heavy burden to bear.
我明白
I know.
我也清楚  我的所作所为
I know--I also know that what I've done,
是不可饶恕的
it's unforgiveable.
你母亲去世后  宝贝...
When you're mother died, honey...
我的内心崩溃了
something inside me broke.
我没能保护好她
I couldn't protect her.
可我仍然对着她的坟墓起誓
And I swore-- I swore on her grave, no less,
我一定会保护好你  可极速把你抓走
that I would protect you, and then Zoom took you,
我崩溃了
and I snapped.
我完全崩溃了
I just snapped.
我无法呼吸  我...
I couldn't breathe, I...
我不能失去另一个仅存的
I couldn't lose the only other person
我爱的人
that I love.
是的  我明白
Yeah. Yeah, I get that.
我理解你为了保护我
I understand why you did everything
所做的一些
you did to protect me.
你才失踪了一天
I mean, you were only missing one day,
我都要不惜一切去找你
and I would have done anything to find you.
但是...
But, I mean...
我想确定那种事不会再发生了
I need to know that that's never gonna happen again.
好吗
Okay?
我晚回家或惹麻烦时
Every time I stay out late or get in trouble,
你不用找我  不用伤及他人
you can't track me down or hurt someone
仅仅以救我为理由
'cause you're trying to save me.
是的  可是你有危险
Yeah, but you're in danger.
-我知道  -好的
- I know. - Okay.
我要向你保证
I will make you a promise.
我保证  我以后会成为
I promise you, I will be the kind of father
让你自豪的父亲
that you can be proud of.
只要你能保证  以后不再离我而去
If you promise me you will never run away from me again.
好的  一言为定
Okay. Okay, deal.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我的小杰西·快客
My little Jesse Quick.
放松  他会来的
Relax, he'll be here.
我该说些什么
What should I say?
我都不知道从何说起
I don't even know where to start.
说实话就好
Just be honest.
发自内心
Speak from your heart.
好
Okay.
沃利·韦斯特
Wally West.
我回家等你
I'll see you at home.
你想见我
You wanted to see me.
是的  我想来着
Yes. I did.
我是说  我想
I mean, I-- I do.
我是想感谢你救了我一命
I just wanted to thank you for saving my life.
我知道那让你付出了巨大代价
And I know that that came at a huge price for you.
我不知道怎么才能报答你
And I don't know how I'll ever repay that.
其实  我要说的是...
I guess, what I wanted to say was that...
我不会浪费这次
I'm not gonna waste this chance
你赋予我的机会
that you've given me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气  沃利
You're welcome, Wally.
你没事吧
You okay?
离我远点儿
Stay away from me.
冰霜杀手要杀你  凯特琳
Killer Frost tried to kill you, Caitlin.
我救了你
I saved your life.
你应该谢谢我
You should thank me.
我只想回家
I just want to go home.
不可以
No.
留下来
Stay.
我想走
I want to leave!
站住  小子
Stay, boy!
不要
No!
求你了
Please.
把我送回地球一
Take me back to my Earth.
知道吗
You know...
我通常利用计算受害者数
I've always measured my success
来衡量我的胜利
by counting the number of victims I've had.
但现在我要扩大范围了
But now I think I'm going to widen my scope.
换成计算我征服的地球数
Start counting the number of Earths I conquer, instead.
你想回家
You want to go home?
我们就回
Then let's go.
毕竟  这一个地球已经
After all, this Earth has already
被我统治了
been brought to its knees.
你来得挺早
You're here early.
是啊
Yeah.
-我睡不着  -我也是
- I couldn't sleep. - Me neither.
我们虽然没靠超能力打败了格雷
I know that we just took down Grey without my powers, but...
但没有超能力  如何能救回凯特琳
I have no idea how to get Caitlin back without them.
不能  艾伦
We can't, Allen.
那我们要怎么做
Then what are we gonna do?
格雷他...
You know, Grey...
格雷绑架我是因为
Grey kidnapped me because
他以为我是这个地球上的哈里森·威尔斯
he thought I was the Harrison Wells from this Earth,
我知道他指的是另一个人
and I know he was talking about another guy,
可我...
but I just...
我不禁会想...
I can't help but think...
我的债依然没有还清
I still haven't paid for what I've done.
什么意思
What does that mean?
我以为  那时候...
I thought, you know, when you--
当我们关闭缺口时
when we closed the breaches,
我就能忘掉我所做的一切
I could just forget about everything I've done,
但我不能
but I can't.
我知道我能做什么了
I realize what I can do.
你会重新获得速度的  艾伦
You are gonna get your speed back, Allen.
而我会帮你实现
And I'm gonna help you do that.
如何实现
How?
再制造一次粒子加速器爆炸
By creating another particle accelerator explosion.